Guide to the Robert College records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Heritage Room/Rare Books (Istanbul & R.C./N.Y. Offices)
  - RC/Henninger Budgets (1975-1982) (Box 58)
  - RC/Henninger Correspondence with Arthur Andersen & Co. (1976-1982) (Box 58)
  - RC/Henninger Lira Barrowing Hanover Trust Co.'s Statements (1975-1978) (Box 58)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1962 May - August) (Box 58)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1962 April - May) (Box 58)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1962 June - September) (Box 58)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1963 January - April) (Box 58)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1963 July - May) (Box 58)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1963 October - July) (Box 58)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1961 May) (Box 58)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence, Includes Hazen, G. Morris (March - April 1961) (Box 58)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1961 August - October) (Box 59)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1961 June - July) (Box 59)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1961 November - December) (Box 59)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1962 January - March) (Box 59)
  - Report and Correspondence re: "Request to Sell a Piece of Land [on Arnavutkoy Campus] for a U.S. Consular Residence" (1973-1979) (Box 59)
  - Correspondence re: Turkish Taxes on Land and Buildings (1972-1977) (Box 59)
  - Building Renovations and Permits, 1983 (Box 59)
  - Plant Survey (1984) (Box 59)
  - Çambel Property (1989) (Box 59)
  - Power of Attorney - May 15, 1991 (Box 59)
  - Legal Counsel (Turkey) - Vakur Versan and Tayar Callu, 1969-1972 (Box 59)
  - Legal Counsel (Robert College) - Ertugal Ceylan, 1973-1981 (Box 59)
  - Legal Counsel (Washington, D.C.) - Steptoe and Johnson, 1969-1974 (Box 60)
  - Legal Counsel (Washington, D.C.) - Steptoe and Johnson, 1975-1982 (Box 60)
  - Huntington Property (Transfer to Hisar Vakt.) (1975) (Box 60)
  - Lawsuits Brought Against RC/ACG by Students (Box 60)
  - Powers of Attorney: (Box 60)
  - Invest Account Documents (Kidder Peabody/Webster Management) (Box 60)
  - Alexander and Green Study on Restricted Endowment Funds, 1964 (Box 60)
  - Cy Pres Proceedings for Charles M. Hall Fund, 1971 (Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous Regarding Huntington Property Transfer (Box 60)
  - Charges Related to the Huntington Property (Box 61)
  - Correspondence from Alfred Ogden II (Box 61)
  - Correspondence from Tricia Staab (Box 61)
  - Death Certificate for Huntington Property (Box 61)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1963 December - October) (Box 61)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1964 January - April) (Box 61)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1965 January - June) (Box 61)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1965 July - November) (Box 61)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1964 May - December) (Box 61)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence ( 1965-1966 October - January) (Box 61)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1966 February - March) (Box 61)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1966 March - December) (Box 61)
  - RC/Ogden Correspondence (1967 January - May) (Box 61)
  - RC/Ogden: (Box 62)
    - General Correspondence (1971-1974) (Box 62)
    - General Correspondence (1974-1976) (Box 62)
    - General Correspondence (1976-1980) (Box 62)
    - General Correspondence re: tax exemption, reorganization of exec. committee (1966-1968) (Box 62)
    - Minutes of the Field Operations Committee (1966-1967) (Box 62)
    - Correspondence re: Reorganization of R.C. (1971) (Box 62)
    - Correspondence (1974-1977) (Box 62)
    - Funds not examined to N.E.G.A. Resolutions (1964) (Box 62)
    - Exhibit to preliminary report on certain funds: Wills (1964) (4 Folders) (Box 62)
    - Second Set of Exhibits to preliminary report on certain funds: wills and testaments (1964) (Box 62)
    - Second Set of Exhibits to preliminary report on certain funds: (Box 62)
    - Correspondence & wills (1964) (Box 62)
    - Sworn trustee consent re: Amendment of RC charter (1972-1973) (Box 62)
    - Approval forms re: Charter amendment (1972) (Box 62)
    - Memoranda re: Not-for-Profit corporation law (1972-1973) (Box 62)
    - Act of Incorporation: Amendment to Charter (1973) (Box 62)
  - RC/Ogden: (Box 63)
    - Memoranda re: Amendment to Charter (1972-1973) (Box 63)
    - Correspondence re: Amendment of RC Charter (1972-1977) (Box 63)
    - "Miscellaneous": bills and resolutions (1968-1971) (Box 63)
    - Geoffrey Wolf re: unpaid loan (1963-1965) (Box 63)
    - Tax Ruling (1964-1968) (Box 63)
    - Lucille Strongham disputes re: termination of employment (1973) (Box 63)
    - Status of resident or non-resident alien re: F.I.C.A. and U.S. income tax (1963-1965) (Box 63)
    - Chalfont-Power of Attorney (1968-1972) (Box 63)
    - Pooled Income Fund: Warner M. Pomerene (1971) (Box 63)
    - Pension for Turks (1966-1968) (Box 63)
    - Records re: Merger with ACG (1958) (2 Folders) (Box 63)
    - Petition to the Board of Regents of the University of the State of New York. Reflects transfer of the Bebek campus to the Republic of Turkey (1971) (Box 63)
    - Jane Wright File: 1958, 1965, 1970 (Box 63)
    - Jane Wright File, 1970 (Box 63)
  - Robert College-Financial Records: (Box 64)
    - Funds/Scholarships (2 Folders) (Box 64)
    - Estates (2 Folders) (Box 64)
    - Building and Real Estate Records (Box 65)
    - Wills and Testaments (Box 65)
    - Personal Records (misc.) (Box 65)
    - Law/Certificate of Reinstatement (Box 65)
    - (8/17/56)/Copyrights/Trustees/Merger (Box 65)
    - RC/Lawrence: (Box 66)
    - Correspondence, Memoranda from Board of Trustees, RC administrators (1959-1960) (Box 66)
    - Reports, Correspondence, Memoranda to Board of Trustees (1961) (Box 66)
    - Correspondence, Memoranda to Trustees from N.Y. Office, R.C. administrators (1962-3) (Box 66)
    - Correspondence, Memoranda from Ogden, Malin, N.Y. Office (1963) (Box 66)
    - Memoranda, reports re: Private Schools' Bill (1963-1964) (Box 66)
    - Correspondence, Memoranda from NY Office, Trustees, re: Private Schools (1964) (Box 66)
    - Trustees' memoranda, reports (1964) (Box 66)
    - Trustees' reports, memoranda (1964) (Box 66)
    - Trustees' Minutes, reports, memoranda, incl. Malin, NY Office (1964) (Box 66)
    - Trustees' Correspondence, Memoranda, incl. memos from Malin (1964) (Box 66)
    - Trustees' Reports, minutes, memoranda (1965) (Box 66)
    - Trustees memoranda, minutes, incl. reports from Bond, Simpson (1965) (Box 66)
    - Trustees' Reports, memoranda, minutes, incl. info re: A.I.D. (Box 66)
    - Security clearance (1965) (Box 66)
    - Search Committee for President (1964-1965) (Box 66)
    - English Program: "Time" Magazines (1991) (Box 67)
    - Curriculum-Lise Curriculum (December 1, 1994) (Box 67)
    - Curriculum (Box 67)
    - Outreach Report-November 2003 (Box 67)
    - Summer Camp-1992 (Box 67)
    - Summer Camp-1993 (Box 67)
    - Summer Camp-1994 (Box 67)
    - Summer Camp-1995 (Box 67)
    - Summer Camp-1998 (Box 67)
    - Summer Camp-2003 (Box 67)
    - Summer Camp report-February 2006 (Box 67)
    - Summer Camp-General Info (Box 67)
    - New Buildings Discussions 86-88 (Box 67)
    - Job Description of Headmaster (Box 67)
    - Articles about RC (Box 67)
    - Model U.N. (Box 67)
    - Alumni/ae and Awards (RC and ACG) (Box 67)
    - Alumni/ae-statistical information (Box 67)
    - Alumnae-ACG (Box 67)
    - RC Alumni Attending U.S. Universities (1979-Present) (Box 67)
    - Historical Items of Interest-Brochures (Box 68)
    - Child Study Center (Box 68)
    - Heritage Committee-Minutes (October 17,1996) (Box 68)
    - Friendly Fund (RC Scholarships USA) (Box 68)
    - RC: Headmaster's Report-Harry A. Dawe (1991) (Box 68)
    - RC: Headmaster's Report-Benjamin D. Williams (October 1992) (Box 68)
    - RC: Headmaster's Report-Benjamin D. Williams (February 1993) (Box 68)
    - RC: Headmaster's Report-Christopher Wadsworth (November 1993) (Box 68)
    - Headmaster's Report (November 1993 and February 1994) (Box 68)
    - RC: Headmaster's Report-Christopher Wadsworth (February 1994 June 1994 November 1994) (Box 68)
    - RC: Headmaster's Report-Christopher Wadsworth (Jan 1995) (Box 68)
    - Headmaster's Report (November 1995) (Box 68)
    - Theater/Drama Curriculum (Box 68)
    - ALA-Seft Contract (Box 68)
    - Philosophy-School Philosophy (Box 68)
    - University Acceptances (Box 68)
    - Direct Entry (Box 68)
    - Direct Admissions Tests (1990) (Box 68)
    - Ministry of Education-Ankara (Box 68)
    - Extracurricular Activities (Box 68)
    - Eyp Quilt (March 1999) (Box 68)
  - RC/Robert Hardy: (Box 69)
    - Hardy, Robert S. (Box 69)
    - Yorgi Sitaras (Scholarship student) (1953-1954) (Box 69)
    - Acting Academic Vice President-Correspondence (1968-1969) (Box 69)
    - Correspondence (1969) (Box 69)
    - RC/Robert Hardy (1969) (Box 69)
    - Correspondence (1970) (Box 69)
    - Scholarships from Sofia American College, Inc. (Box 69)
    - ACG 1958 (Box 69)
    - General Correspondence (1959-1962) (Box 69)
    - General Correspondence (1963-1964) (Box 69)
  - RC/Lawrence:
    - Trustees' memoranda, reports, minutes, incl. info re: selection of Dwight Simpson (1965) (Box 69)
    - Trustees' memoranda, minutes, incl. reports from Simpson, Bond (1965) (3 Folders) (Box 69)
    - Audit reports, budget (1965) (Box 69)
    - Trustees' memoranda, minutes (1966) (Box 69)
    - Trustees' memoranda, minutes, incl. reports from Bond, Simpson (1966) (Box 69)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda, reports from Bond, Simpson (1966) (Box 70)
    - Trustees' memoranda, minutes, re: appointment of acting President Howard Hall (1966-1967) (Box 70)
    - Trustees' memoranda, minutes, incl. info re: search for president (1967) (Box 70)
    - Trustees' memoranda, minutes (1967) (Box 70)
    - Budgets (1967-1968) (Box 70)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda (1968) (Box 70)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda, reports from Bond (1968) (Box 70)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda, reports from Bond, Everton (1968) (Box 70)
    - Trustees' memoranda, minutes, reports from Bond (1968) (Box 70)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda, incl. info re: RC's financial crisis (1968-1969) (Box 70)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda, incl. reports from Bond (1968) (Box 70)
    - Budgets (1968) (Box 70)
    - Memos/correspondence to/from NY office: confidential (Box 70)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda, incl. reports from Everton/Bond (1969) (3 Folders) (Box 70)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda (1969) (Box 70)
    - Trustee minutes, memoranda, info re: Reorganization of RC (1969-1970) (Box 71)
    - Reports to trustees from the chairman (1970-) (Box 71)
    - Trustees' memoranda, minutes, info re: reorganization of RC (1970) (Box 71)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda, Bond, Everton reports, re: reorganization of RC (1970) (Box 71)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda, re: reorganization of RC (1970) (4 Folders) (Box 71)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda, re: reorganization of RC (1971) (Box 71)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda, correspondence (1971) (Box 71)
    - Trustees' minutes, memoranda, reports: info re: reorganization of RC (1971) (Box 71)
    - Trustees' memoranda, correspondence, reports from Rose, Chalfont (1972) (Box 71)
    - Trustees' memoranda, minutes; reports from Rose, Chalfont (1971-1972) (Box 71)
    - Trustees' memoranda, correspondence, reports from Rose, Chalfont (1972-1973) (Box 71)
  - RC/New York Office:
    - Trustees' memoranda, correspondence (1973-1974) (Box 71)
  - Land and Buildings: (Box 72)
    - Space study and Remodeling Proposals for merged school on Arnavutkoy Campus (1969-1971) (Box 72)
    - NY board of regents (Univ. of the State of NY) (1970-1971) (Box 72)
    - "Study of Areas on Arnavutkoy Campus Suitable for Development," (1973) (Box 72)
    - Air-inflated Structures, (1974) (Box 72)
    - Correspondence re: deeds, properties (1909-1957) (Box 72)
    - Land Deeds (Box 72)
    - Misc. Correspondence re land acquisition (1870s-1930s) (Box 72)
    - Triangle property (1968-1983) (Box 72)
    - Campus boundary dispute (1950s) (Box 72)
    - Child Study Center (incl. plans) (1959) (Box 72)
    - Description of RC and ACG properties, manner of acquisition, map (bound) (1920s) (Box 72)
    - Correspondence: "Land of Robert College Excess to Educational Needs and Tax Exemption for Hisar Foundation" (1970s) (Box 72)
  - Correspondence re Law 625 (Box 73)
  - Annual Reports of the Trustees to the Regents of the University of the State of NY (1899-1904) (Box 73)
  - Annual Reports of the Trustees to the Regents of the University of the State of NY (1905-1908) (Box 73)
  - Annual Certificate, Inventory and Affidavit of the Trustees (1885 1886, 1887 1888) (Box 73)
  - Annual Certificate, Inventory and Affidavit of the Trustees (18880 1890 1898) (Box 73)
  - Robert College Seal (photostat) (Box 73)
  - English translation of Law 625 governing Private Educational Institutions of Turkey (June 8, 1965) (Box 73)
  - English translation of Law 625 as amended (June 6, 1983) (Box 73)
  - Act by Commonwealth of Massachusetts to Incorporate American College for Girls (1890) (Box 73)
  - Amendments to Act of Incorporation to remove requirement that members of the Board be Directors of the Women's Board of Missions (1906) (Box 73)
  - Act by Commonwealth of Massachusetts to incorporate the Trustees of the American College for Girls at Constantinople (March 11, 1908) (Box 73)
  - Act of Commonwealth of Massachusetts to change name from Trustees of the American College for Girls at Constantinople to Trustees of the American College (December 15, 1932) (Box 73)
  - U.S. Treasury Department (1954) (Box 73)
  - By-laws as amended (June 21, 1979) (Box 74)
  - By-laws as amended (May 23 1990) (Box 74)
  - By-laws as amended (May 22, 1991) (Box 74)
  - Various Turkish Government Permits and papers regarding the Department of Public Instruction (Box 74)
  - Photographs of Documents from Turkish Government (Box 74)
  - Lausanne Treaty-Correspondence re Treaty 1969-1972 (August 6, 1923) (Box 74)
  - Agreements governing transfer of Bebek campus to Government of Turkey (1971) (Box 74)
  - Documents re RC and ACG exemption from "certain taxes imposed under the Turkish Tax Law" (1953) (Box 74)
  - Documents re Duty-Free Status for Robert College in Turkey (1970s) (Box 74)
  - Bill passed by Grand National Assembly, establishing Bosphorus University (June 3, 1971) (Box 74)
  - Legal status of Robert College property in Turkey (1973) (Box 74)
  - Amendment to Consolidate the Trustees of RC of Istanbul and the Trustees of ACG ( December 18, 1959 #7577) (Box 74)
  - Correspondence: Charter Amendment to reflect that RC no longer operates a Yuksek (1972-1973) (Box 74)
  - Legal Correspondence (1990-) (Box 74)
  - Constitution (1800s) (Box 74)
  - Constitution as amended (1896) (Box 74)
  - Constitution as amended (1931) (Box 74)
  - Constitution as amended (1937) (Box 74)
  - Constitution as amended (March 31, 1965) (Box 74)
  - Incorporation of RC of Constantinople by Act of Legislature of the State of New York Certificate of Incorporation (Xerox) (Feb 19, 1864) (Box 74)
  - Act of NY State Legislature authorizing the Syrian Protestant College and the Trustees of RC of Constantinople to take and hold real and personal estate (May 4, 1864) (Box 74)
  - Act of NY State Legislature to authorize the Trustees of RC of Constantinople amend its certificate of incorporation (May 19, 1896) (Box 74)
  - Amendments to increase the number of Trustees from 6 to 9 (Box 74)
  - Amendment to increase the authorized membership of the Board of Trustees of RC to 15 Board of Regents) (Oct 18, 1923 #3300) (Box 74)
  - Amendment to change the name of the corporation to the Trustees of RC of Constantinople (Feb 15, 1946 #5204) (Box 74)
  - Amendment to change the number of trustees of the Corporation from 15 to not more than 25, nor less than 5 (Jan 28, 1949 #5685) (Box 74)
  - Amendment to change the number of Trustees of the Corporation to not more than 48 nor less than 12, the majority of whom with their successors shall be native born citizens of the USA (Jan 22, 1959 #7384) (Box 74)
  - Constitution as amended (Nov 24, 1958) (Box 74)
  - Resolution re restructuring of Board of Trustees (May 12, 1967) (Box 74)
  - RC Quarterly Robert College Alumni Magazine (ca. Fall 1989-Spring 1995) (Box 75)
  - Constantinople Women's College Bulletin of Information (1927-8, 1931-2) (Box 75)
  - Constantinople Woman's College President's Report/Bulletin (1918-1924) (Box 75)
  - Constantinople Woman's College President's Report/Bulletin (1924-1930) (Box 75)
  - Robert College (Yuksek Okulu) Catalogue (1962-3, 1963-4) (Box 75)
  - Robert College (Yuksek Okulu) Catalogue (1967-8, 1968-9) (Box 75)
  - Miscellaneous Publications of Robert College (Box 76)
  - RC/NY Office:
    - Educational Policy Re: Tenure/Sabbatical/Appointments (1964) (Box 76)
    - Correspondence, Memoranda re: AID Security Clearance Controversy (1964-1965) (Box 76)
    - Law Governing Private Schools (1965) (Box 76)
    - Committee on Academic Freedom and Tenures Proposal (1966) (Box 76)
    - Correspondence, Memoranda re: Academic Freedom and Tenure (1967-1968) (Box 76)
    - RC Historical: Mainly Correspondence to Jane Page, Memos Leading to Merger (1967-1977) (Box 76)
    - Materials Relating to the Reorganization of Robert College – Correspondence, Minutes, Memos (Jan-March 1970) (Box 76)
    - Materials Relating to the Reorganization of RC (April 1970) (Box 76)
    - Materials Relating to the Reorganization of RC (May – June 1970) (Box 76)
    - Materials Relating to the Reorganization of RC (June – July 1970) (Box 76)
    - Investment Committee (1973-1975) (Box 76)
    - Investment Committee (1976-1979) (Box 76)
    - Investment Committee (1980) (Box 76)
    - Investment Committee (1980) (Box 77)
    - Planning Committee Reports and Correspondence Relating Thereto (1969-1970) (Box 77)
    - Nominating Committee for Trustees: Correspondence, Memoranda (1970) (Box 77)
    - "Exhibits I, II, III" re: Constitutional Court Merging, RC-ACG Merger (1971) (Box 77)
    - Nominating Committee for Trustees: Correspondence to/from Jane Page (1970-1973) (Box 77)
    - Margory Boyd Revised Trustee List (November 1969) (Box 77)
    - Trustees Planning Committee Meeting (1969) (Box 77)
    - Nominating Committee for Trustees (1973-1974) (Box 77)
    - Profile of Robert College: 1952-1972 (including ACG) (Box 77)
    - Foshay’s Report and Correspondence (1972) (Box 77)
    - RC Financial: Income & Expense (1972-1976) (Box 77)
    - Fiscal/Audit (1977-1978) (Box 77)
    - The University of the State of New York: Relations with RC (1962-1966) (Box 78)
    - The University of the State of New York: Bureau of Statistical Services (1965-1967) (Box 78)
    - Report of the Near East College Association: James L. Brainerd (1967) (Box 78)
    - Chadbourne-Gilpatrick Survey (1967) (Box 78)
    - Richard Robinson Survey (1967) (Box 78)
    - McPhail Reports (1968-1969) (Box 78)
    - Report on Task Force on International Developmental Assistance & Education (1969) (Box 78)
    - Peterson Presidential Task Force: Correspondence and Information: RC and International Development (1969-1970) (Box 78)
    - Reports of Educational Review Committees re: RC/ACG (1968-1969) (Box 78)
    - Committee Report re: School of Science & Language (1969) (Box 78)
    - Committee Report re: School of Business Administration & Economics (1969) (Box 78)
    - Studgard Reports Re: Engineering School (1968-1969) (Box 78)
    - Semi-Annual Report Program (January 1970-June 1970) (Box 78)
    - Semi-Annual Program Report (July 1970-December 1970) (Box 78)
  - RC/Rose: Peat, Marwick, Mitchell & Co: "RC in Istanbul: The Future of the Merged Lycee" (1971) (Box 79)
  - RC/NY Office: "A Brief Look at American Secondary Schools," Jams Maggart, Edward Webster (1973) (Box 79)
  - RC/NY Office: Annual Report (Nov 1973 – Oct 1974) (Box 79)
  - RC/Lawrence:
    - "Correspondence with Field" – Everton-Lawrence Correspondence (1970) (Box 79)
    - "Correspondence with the Field" – Everton Correspondence (1971) (Box 79)
    - "Correspondence with the Field" – Everton Correspondence (1970) (Box 79)
    - "Correspondence with the Field" – Everton Correspondence (1970) (Box 79)
  - RC/Jim Lawrence:
    - Correspondence between John Chalfort and NY Office (1973-1974) (Box 79)
    - Correspondence, John Chalfort to NY Office (1974-1975) (Box 79)
    - Correspondence between NY Office and James Maggart/John Chalfort (1975-1980) (Box 79)
  - RC/Lawrence:
    - Retirement Fund Dilemma (1975-1976) (Box 79)
    - Trustees’ Memoranda, Correspondence, Reports from Rose (1976-1977) (Box 79)
    - Trustees’ Memoranda, Correspondence, Reports from Rose (1977-1979) (Box 79)
    - Future Needs and Developments Committee: "Ad Hoc," includes Simpson’s "Plan for Improvement" (1955-1965) (Box 79)
    - Future Needs and Developments Committees: Minutes, Memoranda (1966-1977) (Box 80)
    - Washington Committee – Correspondence, Memoranda (1967-1970) (Box 80)
    - Washington Committee – Correspondence, Memoranda (1970) (Box 80)
  - RC/NY Office:
    - Washington Committee – Correspondence, Memoranda (1970) (Box 80)
  - RC/Lawrence:
    - Washington Committee: Includes Lawrence, Page Correspondence with AID (1972-1973) (Box 80)
    - Washington Committee: Includes RC-AID Correspondence (1973) (Box 80)
    - Washington Committee, includes AID-RC correspondence (1975) (Box 81)
    - Trustees’ Planning Committee and 1967 "Report of Planning Committee" (1967-1968) (Box 81)
  - RC/Jim Lawrence:
    - Planning Committee (1968-1969) (Box 81)
  - RC/Lawrence:
    - Trustees’ Planning Committee: reports, memos (1968-1969) (Box 81)
    - Trustees’ Planning Committee: memos, reports (1969) (Box 81)
    - Trustees’ Agenda and Minutes (1969-1970) (Box 81)
    - Trustees’ Agenda and Minutes (1970) (Box 81)
    - Trustees’ Agenda and Minutes (1970) (Box 81)
    - Trustees’ Agenda and Minutes (1971) (Box 81)
    - Grants and Fees, Boardgiving (1977) (Box 82)
    - Policies on Teacher Contracts (1972) (Box 82)
    - Correspondence, includes Page, Lawrence (1972) (Box 82)
    - Reports re: Purpose, Development of RC (1981) (Box 82)
    - Yearend Reports (1981-1982) (Box 82)
    - Yearend Reports, includes Webster Management Reports (1981-1982) (Box 82)
  - RC/Jim Lawrence: AIRCO Pension Plan (1973-1974) (Box 82)
  - RC/Lawrence: Materials re: Securing of Appropriations for RC (1974-1975) (Box 82)
  - RC/Jim Lawrence: Alumni List (1972) (Box 82)
  - RC-ACG/Jim Lawrence: Fundraising Brochures (1950s-1970s) (Box 82)
  - RC-Lawrence:
    - Annual Reports of the Chairman – RC (Fundraising) (1973-1975) (Box 82)
    - "Robert College of Istanbul: Challenge of a New Century," Turkish Summary, T. Halman (Box 82)
    - "Challenge of a New Century" Turkish Translation (Campus) Typed: N.Y. (Box 82)
    - Accreditation Report--10 Year (1995) (Box 82)
    - Self-Evaluation Final (1994-95) (Box 82)
    - Accreditation: 10-Year Review (1995) (Box 82)
    - Accreditation: 10-Year Review (1992-93) (Box 82)
    - Accreditation: 10-Year Review "Part A" of Trustees Evaluation Five Yr. Review (1988) (Box 82)
  - NYSAIS Visiting Committee (1988) (Box 83)
  - One Yr. Report on Recommendations of Visiting Committee (6/84) (Box 83)
  - Self-Study Report: Part I (1983) (Box 83)
  - Self-Study Report: Part II (1983) (Box 83)
  - Evaluation & Accreditation (Box 83)
  - E.C.I.S. (Box 83)
  - Evaluation Study Committee (Box 83)
  - 1983 E.C.I.S. Self-Study (Box 84)
  - Re: Evaluation (Box 84)
  - VHS: "The World of Robert College" Written & Narrated by Talat S. Halman (Box 84)
  - Hisar Vakif (Box 84)
  - Hisar Vakfi (Turkish Foundation) (Box 84)
  - Hisar Foundation (Box 85)
  - Hisar Vakfi (Turkish Foundation) (Box 85)
  - Fax Relating to the Huntington Property (Box 85)
  - Powers of Attorney for Huntington Property (Box 85)
  - Property Transferred to Hisar Educational Foundation (Box 85)